<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Marek&#39;s personal webpage</title>
    <link>https://mnovotny.net/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Marek&#39;s personal webpage</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Marek Novotný, 2025</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mnovotny.net/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Streetscape morphometrics: Expanding momepy to analyze urban form from the street point of view</title>
      <link>https://mnovotny.net/publications/streetscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mnovotny.net/publications/streetscape/</guid>
      <description>Streetscape morphometrics: Expanding momepy to analyze urban form from the street point of view Date: July 23, 2025&#xA;Language: English&#xA;Abstract In this paper, we present momepy.streetscape, a new module of the Python library widely used for morphometric analysis, specifically designed to study streetscapes from a pedestrian perspective. The module enables systematic, in-depth analysis of street-based morphology using vector datasets of the built environment. It quantifies features such as street width, façade continuity, and other compositional attributes that shape pedestrian experience and perception.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turris Sentinel - What has 2024 brought (blogpost)</title>
      <link>https://mnovotny.net/publications/turris_sentinel_2024_blogpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mnovotny.net/publications/turris_sentinel_2024_blogpost/</guid>
      <description>Turris Sentinel - What has 2024 brought blogpost Date: May 16, 2025&#xA;Language: Czech&#xA;About the blogpost My first blogpost on CZ NIC&amp;rsquo;s employee blog.&#xA;What I Covered Project History Data Collection: What anonymized data we gather from participating Turris router users. 2024 Highlights: Key findings and trends from the past year. Gegraphical Distribution of Attacks IPv6 Integration: - Added in December 2024 and comparison between attacks over IPv4. Blogpost Read the full post on CZ.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
